AKASH ADHIKARI

SALESFORCE DEVELOPER

LinkedIn | (+91) 9674647570 | akash.adhikari.dev@gmail.com

Professional Summary

A highly experienced Salesforce Developer with 3 x certifications, specializing in configuring Salesforce **Sales and Service Cloud, Experience Cloud**. Demonstrated ability to analyze, design, and optimize business processes while effectively implementing changes that increase user adoption and promote best practices in the organization.

Experience

Cognizant | Programmer Analyst

Sep 2023 - Present

- Reduced duplicate record creation by 40%.
- Improved Case Management by creating custom Case Queues and auto-escalation rules. Reduced fraudulent charges by 50%.
- Revamped Page Layouts & Lightning Record Pages to improve user experience by 30%.
- Built Custom LWC Components on Experience Cloud for partner self-service.
- Custom lead assignment rules using Apex trigger post lead conversion.
 partner self-service.

Cognizant | Salesforce Developer Intern

Apr 2023 - Aug 2023

- Helping configure objects, fields, page layouts, record types, and apps
 And writing test classes and flows.
- Designing simple reports and dashboards for sales, service, or community Metrics.

Certifications

- Salesforce Certified Platform App Builder
- Salesforce Certified Platform Developer I
- Salesforce Certified Administrator

Education

Bachelor of Technology
 Computer Science and Engineering

Cgpa-9.5 | Jun,2019-Jun,2023